Tell me. What's with the body at the temple?
告诉我 寺庙里那具尸体是怎么回事？
This is Saigen Ninomiya, the monk of Nijoji Temple.
这是二浄寺中的僧侣 名为二宫彩源
The way he was beheaded
他的头颅被割下的方式
is the same as the first incident involving Hayato Ippongi.
与第一位受害者一本木隼人一模一样
And Kouki Shikazono, who knew Hayato Ippongi, was also found dead.
还有鹿苑科希 他与一本木隼人相识 如今也已死亡
Tadashi, you lied and said you didn't know Kouki Shikazono.
忠士 你之前说你并不知道 鹿苑科希此人 你撒谎了
This is your girlfriend, right?
这是你的女友 对吧？
This was at the scene where Kouki Shikazono's body was found.
这个出现在了 发现鹿苑科希尸体的现场
Everything is connected, just like in a Miyuki Miyabe novel.
就像宫部美雪的小说里写的那样 一切都能串联起来
Can you explain what's going on?
你能解释一下这到底是怎么回事吗？
What were you doing with your girlfriend?
你和你的女朋友跑去做什么了？
Tadashi.
忠士
Do you know this man?
你认识这个男人吗？
Spit it out!
从实招来！
Hey.
你出来一下
Yes?
好
What was that just now?
你刚才那一出是搞什么？
I will play the bad cop,
我在扮坏警察
so you can offer him a drink to open his heart...
这样你就可以扮好警察 给他喝水 好让他敞开心扉…
He may be a suspect, but he's also my son!
他也许是嫌犯 但与此同时 他也是我儿子！
Sorry.
抱歉
The way you treated him made me think he's a suspect.
你面对他的态度 让我不自觉地把他当成嫌犯了
How can she fall asleep in this situation?
在这种情况下 她怎么还能睡得着？
I shouldn't have brought her.
我不该带她来的
Worried about Hachi?
你很担心八公吗？
Hachi cares more about Izzy than me.
比起我 八公更在乎伊姬
Izzy's Yokai aura is clouding Hachi's mind.
是伊姬的妖气让八公鬼迷心窍了
You know, I was bullied in elementary school.
你知道吗 小学的时候我被霸凌过
Probably because I'm big and have a different skin color.
估计是因为我体型比较大 肤色和大家不一样
But Hachi stood up for me.
但八公站出来保护了我
He's smaller and weaker than me,
那时他的个子没我高 也没我力气大
but got in between the bullies and me,
但他却站在我和霸凌者之间
drenched in sweat and trembling.
大汗淋漓 浑身发抖
Hachi always sees the good in people,
八公总是能看到别人身上好的一面
even if he ends up suffering himself.
即使最终他会因此受苦
I think he's trying to see the good in Izzy, too.
我想他也是在努力看到 伊姬好的那一面
And you're seeing the good in Hachi, too.
而现在你也在努力看到 八公好的那一面
You're trying to help him.
你在努力帮他
Why did you fight with him, then?
那你为什么和他吵架？
You're awake?
你醒了？
It's not a fight. We ended our friendship.
我们没有吵架 我们绝交了
Did these guys
这些人
try to summon Yokai like I did?
都曾像我一样试图召唤妖怪吗？
Yes. And they were killed by my hand.
没错 他们都死于我手
They're losers who can't do anything without my orders.
如今他们是一群没我的命令 什么都做不了的废物
A little noisy.
还有点吵闹
I'm not a loser like them!
我不是他们那样的废物！
Exactly. There's something only you can do.
没错 有些事只有你能做
Use this to find the whereabouts of their friends.
用这玩意找到他们的朋友目前在哪里
I see.
我懂了
So we're freeing Princess Izuna-imiki
我们这是要 和伊豆之内干姬公主的朋友联手
with the help of her friends.
让她重获自由
And then I'll marry her!
之后我就可以和她结婚了！
You fool!
你这蠢货！
We're going to end her life.
我们是要杀了她
Do it.
快点开干
No.
我不要
This is ridiculous.
真是荒谬至极
I shouldn't have unilaterally doubted you.
我不该单方面怀疑你
Let's have a talk.
我们好好聊聊吧
I'm on your side, no matter what.
无论怎样 我都站在你这边
Of course.
这也是难免的
I've never really
在此之前
listened to you properly until now.
我从没用心听你说过话
Tadashi.
忠士
Please.
拜托
Tell me the truth.
把真相告诉我吧
I summoned an ancient Yokai that travels through shadows.
我召唤了一只 能通过阴影肆意穿行的古代妖怪
And I ended up forming a bond with and dating this Yokai.
后来我和这只妖怪建立了连结 并开始和她约会
But her mission is to free her brethren trapped in the World of Nothing,
但她的同族都被困在虚无世界中 解救他们是她的使命
while a zombie samurai is trying to stop her.
然而与此同时 有个僵尸武士一直在试图阻止她
I wanted to help her somehow,
我想尽我所能帮她一把
but we had a fight and we broke up, so I can't reach her.
但我们吵了一架 分手了 所以我联系不到她
So, she's no longer my girlfriend.
因此 现在她不是我的女朋友了
This is a big problem.
这下麻烦大了
Thanks for sharing.
谢谢你告诉我这些
Let me bring you something to drink.
我去给你拿点喝的
He's totally lost his mind.
他完全疯了啊
I'm going out to get some fresh air.
我出去透透气
Okay.
好
We're here.
我们到了
This place is so old.
这地方古香古色的
Don't touch anything.
什么都别碰
-Bad signal! -You, too. No streaming.
-这里信号好差！ -你也是 不要直播
Okay.
好
Jeez.
哇
Amazing.
好震撼
So many surveillance cameras.
好多监控摄像头啊
My family has been fighting Yokai for generations.
我的家族世世代代都在与妖怪作战
But there doesn't seem to be anyone here.
但是这里好像没人啊
Where's your family, Arisa?
你的家人都去哪了 亚里沙？
Someone's on the ground.
有个人躺在地上
What happened?
出什么事了？
-Are you all right? -Your umbrella, dear.
-你还好吗？ -别忘了打伞 亲爱的
My parents were killed by Yokai.
我的父母被妖怪杀了
So, my uncle manages this house now.
所以现在是我叔叔在打理这栋房子
I see.
这样啊
Anyway, I want you to find a certain scroll here.
总而言之 你们要从这里找到一个卷轴
That's what we're here for.
我们来这就是为了这个
A scroll?
卷轴？
The scroll to send Izzy back to her world.
把伊姬送回她原来的世界的卷轴
I think
我记得
it has a pattern like this.
那幅卷轴上应该有这样的图案
You're a terrible artist.
你的画技也太差了
From here?
在这里找？
Hachi.
八公
Can you hear me?
你能听到我的声音吗？
Izzy? Is that you?
伊姬？是你吗？
What is this? I can hear her voice in my head.
这是什么情况？ 她的声音在我的脑袋里回响
HE NEEDS A DRUG TEST!
需要做药检！
I heard your inner scream.
我听到了你内心的尖叫
It seems our bond has evolved through our hearts' connection.
看来因为我们的心贴得更近了 我们的连结也升级了
But we've broken up already.
可是我们已经分手了啊
Yokai don't easily discard bonds once formed.
一旦与伴侣建立连结 妖怪是不会轻易放弃这段关系的
Where are you now?
你现在在哪儿？
What? How?
诶？怎么会？
This ain't good!
这下可糟了！
This is the last time I'm helping you.
这是我最后一次帮你
Izzy?
伊姬？
The suspect has fled the police. Officers need to...
嫌犯已逃离警局 各位警员需要…
Sir!
长官！
Tadashi is...
忠士他…
Where did you get this car?
这辆车是你从哪弄来的？
I borrowed it from my new friend in this era.
是我问这个时代新结识的朋友借的
A true friend is a great blessing.
拥有一位真正的朋友是莫大的福气
How's your work?
你干得怎么样了？
The other day,
那天
when I infiltrated Princess Izuna-imiki's friend's game account,
我侵入伊豆之内干姬公主的 朋友的游戏账号时
I planted a virus.
我种下了一种病毒
We can track their location with GPS.
这让我们可以通过GPS 追踪他们的位置
Good job.
干得好
If I don't do well, I'll be under some painful spell again!
如果我不好好干 你又要用咒语让我痛苦不堪！
Listen, everyone!
各位听好了！
Here's the plan.
我们的计划是这样的
We're going to capture a human who bonded with a Yokai.
我们要抓捕一个 和妖怪建立了连结的人类
He's a weak man.
他很弱
If we kill him, the Yokai bonded to him will die, too.
只要我们杀了他 和他建立连结的妖怪也会死去
It's a pre-celebration.
我们可以提前庆祝了
Sing, my undead!
歌唱吧 我的活死人们！
Can't find it at all.
完全找不到啊
Where did Arisa go?
亚里沙去哪儿了？
You know,
那个
you seem to be the type
你看起来是那种
who likes intellectual women like Arisa.
喜欢像亚里沙这样的知性女孩的人
What?
什么？
Well, since we're talking
既然我们正好
about this topic now,
说到这个话题
what kind of girl do you like?
你喜欢什么样的女孩？
What?
诶？
I...
我…
Well...
这个嘛…
It's Hachi.
是八公打来的
Not answering?
你不接吗？
Our friendship is over.
我们已经绝交了
Pick it up!
快接！
All right.
行吧
You've got some nerve calling me.
你竟然还敢给我打电话
Tanuki, we have to stop Izzy!
狸 我们必须阻止伊姬！
Well, that sounds tough.
是嘛 听起来并非易事呢
I know! I was wrong.
我知道！是我错了
Remember? We're no longer friends.
你不记得了吗？ 我们的友谊已经结束了
I'll apologize in person. Where are you?
我当面跟你道歉 你在哪儿？
We're at the Renjo residence where Arisa was born.
我们在亚里沙从小生活的连城宅邸
Hey!
喂！
Was that Hikari?
刚才是小光在说话吗？
I'll send you the address.
我马上把地址发给你
Buy me ramen next time.
下次请我吃拉面
Thanks, Hikari!
多谢 光！
Tanuki, I'm coming soon.
狸 我这就赶过去
I haven't forgiven you yet!
我还没原谅你呢！
Damn.
见鬼
Coming through. Excuse me.
借过 不好意思
Foolish Yokai.
愚蠢的妖怪
Disappear!
快消失！
Disgusting.
真恶心
Hey, Yokai.
嘿 妖怪
I'm better at transformations than you Yokai, don't you think?
我的变形能力 比你们妖怪强多了 你不觉得吗？
Troublesome.
真是麻烦
Anyone can undergo a transformation.
我可以变成任何人
Jeez. Transforming into a Yokai is creepy.
天呐 变成妖怪可真够恶心的
I wonder if you could find me?
你能在茫茫人海中找到我吗？
I expected you to come, rogue Yokai.
我早就猜到你会来 你这暴躁的妖怪
Battle music, start!
战曲 开奏！
The time has finally come!
这个时刻终于到来了！
That's right. The time to end Yokai has come.
没错 正是杀死妖怪的好时机
Let me explain.
我来解释一下
This whip of light will cut you into pieces,
这光之鞭能将你碎尸万段
leaving no trace...
不留下任何痕迹…
What's that sound?
那是什么动静？
-What? -Who is that?
-什么情况？ -那是谁？
What's going on?
出什么事了？
This is bad.
这下糟了
So many of them.
对方来了好多人
Don't worry.
别担心
This mansion has a hybrid defense of magic circles and cutting-edge tech.
这座宅邸拥有防御法阵 结合最新科技产品的多层防御系统
They can't...
他们绝对无法…
We're okay... Right?
我们不会有事…吧？
Shit.
见鬼
We've got to find it!
我们必须尽快找到它！
Now is not the time for that! We've got to run!
现在没时间找东西了！ 我们得赶快逃跑
Wait.
再等一下
What?
怎么了？
Close it! Quick!
把门关上！快点！
I can't! He's strong!
我顶不住了！他的力气好大！
Aero.
升空
You.
你
Give up.
放弃抵抗吧
Where's the kid?
那孩子在哪儿？
I'm right here!
我在这儿！
Hachi!
八公！
You idiot! Run!
笨蛋！快跑啊！
Like a bug flying into the fire.
简直是飞蛾扑火
-Time-out! -It's time-out!
-暂停一下！ -中场休息！
No such thing!
休息什么休息！
Listen to me.
你听我说
If you die, she will also die.
只要你死了 她也会死
That solves everything.
那样就天下太平了
If you kill me, Izzy's anger will spin out of control!
如果你杀了我 伊姬会暴怒到失去理智
That's a lie!
胡说！
It's true.
是真的
Otherwise, I wouldn't show up myself. So just listen.
否则我怎么会只身来见你 所以你仔细听我说
We're looking for a scroll of spells
我们在找一幅咒语卷轴
to sever the bond between Hachi and Izzy
用以切断八公和伊姬之间的连结
and send the Yokai back to the World of Nothing.
并将那只妖怪送回虚无世界
Enough with the killings.
不要再互相杀戮了
You're sending her back to the World of Nothing?
你们要把她送回虚无世界？
It's not an easy spell for someone inexperienced like you.
像你这样缺乏经验的人 很难使用那样的咒语
Besides, you might be her target because...
再者说 也许你也是她的目标 因为…
You are one of the chosen ones by the Five Spears.
你也是被五矛选中之人
The Five Spears?
五矛？
The Five Spears are the clans
五矛组织是500年前
that saved this world from Yokai 500 years ago.
从妖怪手中救下这个世界的几大家族
Ippongi, Ninomiya,
一本木家、二宫家
Mikurube, Yomoda and Goromaru
三回部家、下田家和五郎丸家
are the five clans that make up the Five Spears.
便是组成五矛组织的五大家族
Having won the battle against Yokai,
在战胜妖怪后
the Five Spears became known as Guardians,
被世人称为“守护者”的五矛
who quietly sealed away Yokai.
在暗地里将妖怪封印
And the Five Spears have continued to inherit that power to this day.
之后 五矛家族 将他们的力量传承至今
However, there were problems, too.
然而 这也导致了一些问题
Their power has been
他们因自己的力量
targeted by Yokai many times.
屡屡成为妖怪的目标
Worried about the future, the Five Spears
五矛组织出于对未来的担心
decided to share their powers to protect it.
决定分出他们的力量 好让几大家族得以延续
That's why the Renjo family
因此连城家族
was chosen.
被选中了
The head of the Five Spears, Saori Goromaru,
五矛组织的头领 五郎丸纱织
gave an amulet to a young child
将一枚护身符赠予一名幼童
to secretly perform a ritual and bestow them with power.
悄悄举行仪式 赐予他们力量
This ritual
这场仪式
must have been your fate for being born into the Renjo family.
是你出生在连城家族 而必须背负的命运
The bracelet, harboring a special power, is the greatest proof of this.
这只蕴藏着特别之力的手镯 便是强有力的证明
It's a gift from my deceased father.
这是我已故的父亲送给我的
I, too, serve the Five Spears.
我也为五矛组织效力
That's why, as someone with power, I am targeted by Izzy.
所以作为拥有这种力量的人 我自然是伊姬的目标
Exactly.
正是如此
-Uncle? -Arisa.
-叔叔？ -亚里沙
Are you at the mansion?
你在老宅吗？
You see...
是这样的…
I'm a chosen one of the Five Spears.
我是被五矛组织选中的人
Has Tenkai come to you?
天海去找你了吗？
Were Father and Mother also chosen by the Five Spears?
我爸妈也是被五矛组织选中的人吗？
Your father served the Five Spears.
你父亲是五矛的人
That's why he was killed by Yokai.
所以他才会被妖怪杀害
You tried to keep me away from this world
你想尽力让我远离 这个妖人相争的世界
by not telling me about the Yokai power.
所以你从没把妖力的事告诉我
The Renjo family's destiny is much grander than you can imagine.
连城家族的命运之宏伟 远超你的想象
I don't care about fate.
我不在乎什么命运
I just hate that Yokai killed my parents.
我只是憎恨杀害我父母的妖怪
Hey, Arisa. Arisa!
嘿 亚里沙！
You were right.
你说得没错
If that's the case,
既然如此
I know a way to send Izzy back to the World of Nothing.
我想到一个 将伊姬送回虚无世界的办法
You can use me as bait to lure Izzy.
你可以以我为饵 诱伊姬入套
That's the only way.
这是唯一可行的办法
And I want this more than anyone else.
我想完成这件事的心 比任何人都迫切
But we still haven't found the scroll to send Izzy back to her world.
可是我们还没找到 将伊姬送回去的卷轴呢
To the right.
往右移
To the left.
往左移
Can we really find it?
我们真的能找到吗？
Tanuki.
狸
I'm really sorry.
我真的很抱歉
It feels so good to be right.
作为正确的那一方感觉真好
You were right, Tanuki.
你说得没错 狸
Izzy can't stay in this world.
伊姬不能留在这个世界
You really fell for her.
你真的爱上她了
Back in elementary school, you treated me just like everyone else,
上小学的时候 尽管我是个混血儿
despite me being mixed race.
你却从不区别对待我
It made me happy.
这让我很开心
It's lame to push away my best friend
因为你有一个妖怪前女友
just because you have a Yokai ex-girlfriend.
就和我最好的朋友分道扬镳 那也太不值了
I have one question. When Tenkai attacked you earlier,
我有时想问你 早先天海攻击你的时候
you said Izzy's anger would spin out of control.
你说伊姬会暴怒到失去理智
Did you make that up?
这是你编的吗？
You knew it?
你猜到了？
You...
你真是…
Shit!
糟糕！
BENITARO
贝尼塔罗
Tomorrow is the ELEGENDS tournament!
明天“电竞传奇”联赛就开赛了！
I'll forgive your past mistakes.
我可以既往不咎
So, listen up. Don't be late tomorrow.
所以你听好了 明天千万别迟到
This is a fierce battle where we give everything!
这会是一场苦战 我们要为此拼尽全力！
Do you understand? Answer me!
你听懂了吗？回答我！
Hello?
喂？
Found it!
找到了！
We can send Izzy back to her world with this.
我们可以用这个 把伊姬送回她原来的世界
So, where do we lure Izzy?
那我们该把伊姬引到哪里？
Here, right?
不引到这里吗？
It's our home.
这是我们的主场
The Yokai power in this mansion is incomplete.
这座宅邸的妖力有缺损
Even I could easily break it.
就连我都能轻易粉碎它
Right.
也对
First, we need a place where we can set up
首先 我们得找一个地方
a powerful magic circle to capture that Yokai.
在那里布置用以捕捉妖怪的强大法阵
It can't just be anywhere.
不是随便什么地方都行
We need to cast the spell
我们需要在一个
where conflict and hatred are swirling.
充满冲突和矛盾的地方施咒
Is there such a place?
有这种地方吗？
We need a battlefield akin to dedicating everything to a fierce struggle.
我们需要一片有着 拼尽全力厮杀苦战的气氛的战场
"A battlefield akin to dedicating everything to a fierce struggle"?
“一片有着拼尽全力 厮杀苦战的气氛的战场”？
It's a battlefield of fierce struggle!
我们要为此拼尽全力！
That's right!
我想到了！
So, it's decided, then.
那就这么定了
That's where
我们就在那里
we'll end her.
了结她
Banishing her from this world, right?
你指的是 把她驱逐出这个世界 对吧？
I'm very sorry.
非常抱歉
It seems I made a mistake
看来是我错了
leaving it to you.
不该把这件事交给你办
Oh, my.
真是的
What a spirited young fox.
真是一只充满活力的小狐狸
MUKURO POLICE STATION
六畔警察署
Sir!
长官！
The chief is calling.
署长打电话来了
Are you going to look for Tadashi?
你要去找忠士吗？
You'll be punished.
你会受处分的
Get out.
下车
My son is more important.
对我而言 我的儿子更重要
Cool! I'll accompany you, sir.
真酷！我陪你去 长官
Here, Arisa.
给你 亚里沙
Thanks.
谢谢
Okay. Are you all ready?
好了 大家都准备好了吗？
The time has come. All right!
时机已到 我们走吧！
Charge forth!
准备开战！